J. Gus Liebenow Collection, 1882-2011 LCP2007/02
Liberian Collections
- Writings
  - Other Writing Projects
    - "Twenty Five Years of African Independence" – Book and Conference,, undated, 1982-1984 (Box 17)
    - World Book, Inc.,, undated, 1978-1991 (Box 17)
    - Writings by Other Authors Re: African Politics, 1982-1988 (Box 17)
    - Zimbabwe News Clippings,, undated, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Published Materials
    - "Africa: Four Crises of Political Development", 1979 (Box 17)
    - "African Economic History" (excerpt), 1976 (Box 17)
    - "Agriculture, Education, and Rurual-Transformation – With Particular Reference to East Africa", 1969 (Box 17)
    - "American Diplomacy in a New Era" (chapter), 1961 (Box 17)
    - "'Aspects of International Retaliations in Africa' - The Quest for Africa Unity", 1978 (Box 17)
    - "The Chief in Sukuma Local Government", 1959 (Box 17)
    - "Current History" (article), 1980-1983 (Box 17)
    - "The Establishment of Legitimacy in Dependency Situation", undated (Box 17)
    - "Federalism in Rhodesia and Nyasaland", 1963 (Box 17)
    - "Inquiry Magaine", 1980 (Box 17)
    - "Issues" A Quarterly Journal of Africanist Opinion, 1979 (Box 17)
    - "Legitimacy of Alien Relationship" The Nyaturu of Tanganyika", 1961 (Box 17)
    - "Liberia: Growth Without Development", 1967 (Box 17)
    - "Liberia: The Path to Civilian Rule", 1982 (Box 17)
    - "Liberian Political Opposition in the Post-Election", 1988 (Box 17)
    - "Politics in Africa" (chapter), 1966 (Box 17)
    - "Responses to Planned Political Change in Tanganyika Tribal Groups", 1956 (Box 17)
    - "Survey of Background Material for the Study of the Government of East Africa", 1954 (Box 17)
    - "A Tanganyika Federation: The Sukuma", 1960 (Box 17)
  - Publishing Houses
    - CLIO Press, 1988-1989 (Box 17)
    - Cornell University Press, undated, 1966-1986 (Box 17)
    - Greenwood Press,, undated, 1989 (Box 17)
    - Harcourt, Brace and World, Inc., 1963-1965 (Box 17)
    - Harper and Row Publishers,, undated, 1962-1968 (Box 17)
    - IC Publications, 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - IU Press, 1975 (Box 17)
    - IU Press Act: "Liberia: Quest for Democracy", undated (Box 17)
    - IU Press: Contract,, undated, 1983-1986 (Box 17)
    - IU Press: Marketing,, undated, 1983-1987 (Box 17)
    - IU Press: Promo for "African Politics: Crises and Challenges",, undated, 1985-1987 (Box 17)
    - Lerner Publications Company,, undated, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Northwestern University Press, undated, 1969-1980 (Box 17)
    - Publications Correspondence, undated, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Reference Publications, Inc., undated, 1981-1983 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Publication Materials, undated, 1978-1980 (Box 17)
- Restricted Files (Box 18)
  This collection is not open to researchers. Please speak to the archivist if you have any questions.
  - Carter, Gwendolen, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Carter, Jeanette, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Dunn, Elwood,, undated, 1981-1988 (Box 18)
  - Gallimore, Timothy, undated (Box 18)
  - Glover, Arthur, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Goldman, Etel, 1979-1980 (Box 18)
  - Guthrie, Charles, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Hale, Jon, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Healey, Ellen, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Healey, Robert, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Heilman, Bruce, 1988-1990 (Box 18)
  - Hershfield, Allan,, undated, 1986-1988 (Box 18)
  - Hicks, Barbara, 1983-1984 (Box 18)
  - Hillenberg, Marie, 1975-1980 (Box 18)
  - Holmquist, Frank,, undated, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Hopkins, Barbara, 1985-1988 (Box 18)
  - Hyden, Goran, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Jones, David, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Kante, Mamadou, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Kapansa, Kenneth, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Karp, Ivan,, undated, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Kellar, Edmond, 1976-1980 (Box 18)
  - Kinman, Karen, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Komyatte, Jude, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Konneh, Augustine, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
  - Knoll, Arthur, undated (Box 18)
  - Kramer, David, 1975-1987 (Box 18)
  - Krause, David, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Lake, Mary, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Lambert, Louis, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Leighton, Neil, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Leopold, Robert, 1983–1984 (Box 18)
  - Lockett, Sylvia, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Lofchie, Michael, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Lucas, John, 1987-1989 (Box 18)
  - Luneburg, Robert, undated (Box 18)
  - Malik, Barry, undated, 1969-1978 (Box 18)
  - Martin, Brad, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Martin, Phyllis, 1978-1981 (Box 18)
  - Martin, Richard, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Masabi, Humeleng,, undated, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Massing, Andreas, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - McCormick, 1987-1990 (Box 18)
  - McCoy, Frieda,, undated, 1984-1987 (Box 18)
  - McHenry, Dean,, undated, 1979-1985 (Box 18)
  - Mellinger, Virginia Lee,, undated, 1980-1981 (Box 18)
  - Merritt, Hollis, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Meyer, John,, undated, 1988-1990 (Box 18)
  - Miller, David, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Morgan, E. Philip, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Ndama, William,, undated, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Ndlovu, Scotch, 1980-1981 (Box 18)
  - Newman, David, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Nimtz, August, 1975-1977 (Box 18)
  - Nuth, Timothy, 1990 (Box 18)
  - O'Connor, James, 1982 (Box 18)
  - O'Meara, Patrick,, undated, 1980-1989 (Box 18)
  - Ogundimu, Folu, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Olorunsola, Victor,, undated, 1971-1986 (Box 18)
  - Page, Cindy, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Painter, Colin, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Parker, Richard, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Patterson, Craig,, undated, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Perinbaum, B. Marie, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Pigozzi, Mary,, undated, 1977 (Box 18)
  - Preye-Okosi, Debs, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Robbins, Ed, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Reed, William Cyrus,, undated, 1980-1986 (Box 18)
  - Robertson, Claire, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Romero, Patricia, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Ronen, Dov, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Rosberg, Carl,, undated, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Sawyer, Amos, 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Schlager, Edella, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Schlitt, Michael, undated, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Schrag, Norman, undated (Box 18)
  - Schroeder, Deborah,, undated, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Scott, David J., 1990 (Box 18)
  - Segal, Ed, undated (Box 18)
  - Segal, Marcia, 1984 (Box 18)
  - Segarra, Eric, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Seyon, Patrick, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Shaw, Tim,, undated, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Siegmann, William, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - Simpson, Dick, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Skylar, Richard, 1975-1981 (Box 18)
  - Smit, Alphons, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Spitzer, Manon, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Stockton, Rex, 1977-1984 (Box 18)
  - Stryker, Richard, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Sundiata, Ibrahim,, undated, 1979-1989 (Box 18)
  - Stanley, Nzefeh, 1980-1983 (Box 18)
  - Tannenbaum, Eric,, undated, 1977-1978 (Box 18)
  - Tarpeh, James, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Thomson, James, 1977-1980 (Box 18)
  - Toler, Deborah,, undated, 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Tolley, Dayna,, undated, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Trump, Tom,, undated, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Tuck, Michael,, undated, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Ullman, Uri, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Ullrich, Greg,, undated, 1984-1985 (Box 18)
  - Utomi, Patrick, 1981 (Box 18)
  - Vaughan, James, 1978 (Box 18)
  - Vieceli, Jackie,, undated, 1977-1989 (Box 18)
  - Weakland, Kathleen,, undated, 1988-1989 (Box 18)
  - Weidman, Barton E.,, undated, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Wenkert, David,, undated, 1984-1985 (Box 18)
  - Wilz, Tom,, undated, 1986 (Box 18)
  - Winchester, Brian,, undated, 1983-1989 (Box 18)
  - Winter, Michael, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Wunsch, James S.,, undated, 1976-1978 (Box 18)
  - Wynne, Susan, 1987-1988 (Box 18)
  - Yahne, Scott E., 1989 (Box 18)
  - Yoder, Michael,, undated, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Yeager, Rodger, 1987 (Box 18)